blood.co.uk 2017-07-11

# Privacy | Blood Donation

> Collection of personal information  
> Right of access  
> Terms of use

## Collection of personal information

You may use the website without providing any personal information. However, if you wish to order promotional materials or contact us using the online forms, you are requested to provide relevant contact details, such as your name, e-mail and postal address and contact telephone number to enable us to provide the information your require.

Online forms provide a means for you to register as a blood donor, join the NHS Organ Donor Register and Bone Marrow Registers, request further information or raise queries. In some cases you may add comments or queries which might also contain personal information. When you register as a donor, you will be required to fill in mandatory fields indicated by an asterisk.

NHS Blood and Transplant will keep records on blood donors, donations and test results for at least 30 years.  All records are kept securely.

We will use this information:

  * To communicate with you via post, email, phone call and SMS in relation to sending session invitations or information about other donation matters
  * To ensure the safety of donors and patients
  * For clinical audit to assess and improve our service
  * For research
  * For management and administration

We may compare details with central NHS records or those of other data processors to stay in touch. We are committed to protecting the confidentiality of our donors and to meeting our responsibilities under the Data Protection Act 1998. Read our guide for blood donors about [your rights and our responsibilities](https://nhsbtdbe.blob.core.windows.net/umbraco-assets-blood/1263/your-rights-and-our-responsibilities.pdf "Your rights and our responsibilities.pdf") (PDF 0.4MB).

We automatically track certain information about all our website users based on what you do on the site. We use this information to analyse our users' demographics, interests, and behaviour on the site to understand and serve you better . This information we capture for this purpose does not identify any user.

We may contact you from time to time to inform you about developments in our services, to let you know how we have used the blood that you give and to encourage you to continue to do so.

## Right of access

Under the provisions of the Data Protection Act 1998, you are entitled to a copy of any personal information held by us. To request a copy, please contact us in writing to the address below. A fee may be charged for providing your information.

### Who to contact

Please send any comments or questions relating to this privacy policy or personal information held by us to the address below, or by email to [**dpofficer@nhsbt.nhs.uk**](mailto:dpofficer@nhsbt.nhs.uk).

NHSBT Customer Services  
Second Floor, Oak House,  
Reeds Crescent,  
Watford,  
Herts,  
WD24 4QN

If you are requesting access to your personal data, please ensure that your application contains a signature that we can check against what we already hold to verify your identity.

## Terms of use

### General

NHS Blood and Transplant (NHSBT) is a Special Health Authority within the NHS, responsible for managing NHS Blood and Transplant.

This website (excluding linked sites) is controlled by NHS Blood and Transplant. The site can be accessed from countries around the World. As each of these places has laws that may differ from those of England by accessing the site both you and we agree that the laws of England shall apply to all matters arising from or relating to the use and contents of this site. You also agree and hereby submit to the non-exclusive jurisdiction of the courts of England with respect to such matters.

By accessing and using this website in any way, including, without limitation, browsing the website, registering as a donor, using any information, using any content, using any services, downloading any materials, you agree to and are bound by these Legal Notices. If you do not accept these Legal Notices in full, please cease using this website immediately.

### Terms of Use for Users of the Online Blood Donor Register

The terms of use and privacy policy for the NHS Blood & Transplant website govern your use of NHS Blood & Transplant Online Blood Donor Register. In addition, the following terms apply:

We may amend these terms of use from time to time, and the revised version will be effective when displayed here.

If accessing any part of the Online Blood Donor Register that requires you to enter a password you agree:

To ensure that any details which you supply to us to register for such access are accurate and to update your profile promptly if any of the details which you have supplied to us about you change;

To keep any personal login name and any password confidential, and to be responsible for any loss or damage resulting from use of your password by any third party;

That we reserve the right to terminate your access to the Online Blood Donor Register should we consider that your use of the register is detrimental to the Online Blood Donor Register or to other users.

We shall use any personal information you submit to the Online Blood Donor Register and other information we hold about you in accordance with our privacy policy. In particular, we shall use the information (including sensitive personal information relating to your physical health) to provide you with a blood donor information service as described. By registering for the service through this form, you give your consent to such use of your personal information.

While we will use our reasonable endeavours to ensure that the information provided by the Online Blood Register is accurate, the register (including records of blood stocks, your blood type and quantities of blood donated) is provided to support your own records and you should always check with an appropriately qualified health professional before donating blood.

By registering online as a blood donor, you agree to the NHS Blood & Transplant's general terms of use (including disclaimers), privacy policy and these terms of use.

### Use of user-generated content

We reserve the right to include content from sites including but not limited to You Tube, Twitter, Vine, Instagram and Facebook. We do not control the privacy practices of these other sites. Users of such sites take full responsibility for their own content. We use our best endeavours to protect the interests of the individuals featured in the content on our website.

Our use of any user-generated images and video for campaigning purposes will not involve the collection or storage of personal data. No information will be passed to third parties or transferred overseas.

Survey data will be held anonymously and separately, and no identifiable or personal information will be associated with it. All data will be transferred over secure connections.

For privacy and terms applicable to these social media sites please use the links below:

<https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>  
<https://twitter.com/privacy>  
<https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>  
<https://vine.co/privacy>  
<http://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/>

### Campaign apps and tools

Tools and apps provided by NHSBT for users to generate shareable posts on social media are intended for awareness-raising only. Any Facebook data (profile picture) accessed by a tool or app is used to personalise the resulting asset and is not used for marketing or made available to third parties. Survey responses will be used for ongoing campaign planning purposes, however no personal data will be shared.

The general privacy and terms published by NHSBT apply to content provided by and your use of any NHSBT Facebook (or other social media) app. For full details see privacy and legals.

This additional provision applies to your use of any social media app:

Comments and other content made in response to posts created via our app(s) will not be monitored by NHSBT and will be subject to the social media site's terms and conditions.
